Mary van Kleeck Papers, 1849-1998
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE1849-1981
  - Friends and associates
    - Flexner, Eleanor 1956-57 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley 1954 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Fosdick, Raymond B. 1924, 1931 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Fox, R. M. 1929 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Fulbright, Senator J. William 1961 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - G 1905, 1923-51 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Garza, Makedonio, Professor 1939-43 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Gifford, Helen W., Young Women's Christian Association 1923-41 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Gilbreth, Lillian M. 1928 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Gillman, Joseph M., Inter-Professional Association for Social Insurance 1938 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Gilson, Mary 1923-31 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Givens, Meredith B. 1931-36 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Glenn, John M., Russell Sage Foundation, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation--General--Correspondence] (Box 26)
    - Goldmark, Pauline 1923-29 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Goldschmidt, Mr. and Mrs. Alfons 1935-42 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Gompers, Samuel, American Federation of Labor 1923 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Grierson, Margaret S. 1947-65, [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--Correspondence with Sophia Smith Collection] (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Gropius, Walter 1938, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Gross, John E., Colorado State Federation of Labor 1932-33 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Gross, N. B. 1927-28 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Gutkind, Erwin A. 1936-37 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - H 1892-1905, 1922-49 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Hamilton, Alice, Hull House 1924-34 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Hamilton, Berta 1930-42 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Harrison, Shelby M., Russell Sage Foundation, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation--General--Correspondence] (Box 26)
    - Harper, Elsie D., Young Women's Christian Association 1934 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Hartogs, Dr. Rene 1932-48 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Hartwell, Albion A., IPA 1935-37 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Harvey, Constance, Smith College 1957 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Hase, Dr. Felix 1934-36, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation--Department of Industrial Studies--Special projects--German Coal Industry] (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Haskins, Charles H. 1923 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Hathaway, King 1938-41 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Heidl, F. X. 1929 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Henry, Alice, National Women's Trade Union League 1922-36 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Hill, Dorothy P. 1933-34 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Hoover, Herbert 1922-26 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Hudson, Manley O. 1924 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Hurlbutt, Mary E., New York School of Social Work 1933 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Hyde, Maxwell P. 1934-35 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - I 1904, 1921-40 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - J 1904-05, 1924-55 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - Jackson, Alice, Smith College 1903-04, undated (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Jerome, Harry 1923-24 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Johnson, Alvin S. 1931-34 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Johnson, F. Ernest, Federal Council Of Churches 1922-24, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Johnston, Alma E. 1924-26 (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - K 1899-1905, 1922-49 (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - Kamaladevi, Mme. (Kamaladevi Chattopadhyaya) 1939-41 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - Kammet, Lawrence, Social Work Today 1938-39 (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - Keir, Malcolm 1922-25 (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Keller, Helen 1940-42 (Box 26, Folder 42)
    - Keller, William 1922 (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - Kelley, Florence 1929 (Box 26, Folder 44)
    - Kellogg, Paul U. 1925-46 (Box 26, Folder 45)
    - Keynes, J. Maynard 1930 (Box 26, Folder 46)
    - Kincaid, W. W., IRI 1928-29 (Box 26, Folder 47)
    - King, W. L. Mackenzie 1921-24 (Box 26, Folder 48)
    - King, Wilford I. 1931-35 (Box 26, Folder 49)
    - Kingsbury, John A. 1933-43 (Box 26, Folder 50)
    - Kingsbury, Susan, Bryn Mawr College 1931-38 (Box 26, Folder 51)
    - Knight, Howard K., National Conference of Social Work 1928-47 (Box 26, Folder 52)
    - Kraus, Dr. Hertha 1928-33 (Box 26, Folder 53)
    - L 1923-61 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - La Dame, Mary, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation--Department of Industrial Studies--Special projects--Filene Store] (Box 27)
    - LaFollette, Senator Robert M. 1931-32 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Laidler, Harry W., League for Industrial Democracy 1932-38 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Lamont, Corliss 1933-89 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Lansburgh, Richard 1924-31 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Larson, C. Theodore 1936-45, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Industrial Relations Institute--Publications, "Planning for Productivity"] (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Lasker, Bruno 1924-25 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Lattimore, Owen 1938, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Communism] (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Leonard, Louise, Young Women's Christian Association 1922-24 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Leslie, Mabel, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Bryn Mawr Summer School for Workers; National Women's Trade Union League] (Box 27)
    - Lewis, John L., United Mine Workers of America 1933-38 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Lindeman, Eduard. C., New York School of Social Work 1933-39 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Lindsay, Samuel McCune 1927-38, undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Lippmann, Walter 1933 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Lombardo-Toletano, Vincente, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Industrial Relations Institute--Subjects] (Box 27)
    - Lorwin, Lewis L. 1930-41 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Lounsbury, Charles E. 1932 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Lovett, Robert Morss 1940 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Lübbe, Erich 1928-29 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Lynd, Robert S. 1924-25 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - M 1896-51, undated (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Mackay, R. J. 1929-32 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Magnusson, Leifur, International Labor Office 1928-35 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Maher, Amy G. 1903-23, undated (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Masaryk, Alice 1932 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Mason, Lucy Randolph 1938 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - McCausland, Elizabeth 1930 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - McCulloch, Rhoda E., The Woman's Press 1922-36 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - McCullough, E. W. 1930-31 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - McGovern, George 1961 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - McIver, Robert M. 1925 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Meriam, Lewis 1924-25 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Meshlauk, V. I. 1931-33 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Miller, Helen Clarkson, Young Women's Christian Association 1923 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - Miller, Spencer, Jr. 1922-36 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Mitchell, Broadus 1933 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Morris, Elizabeth C. F. 1930-39 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - Morse, Stearns 1935-36 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - Murdock, James 1924-25 (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - Muste, A. J. 1932 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Myers, James, Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America 1922-1930 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - N 1903-61 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - Nathan, Otto 1948-58, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Industrial Relations Institute--Subjects] (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - Neilson, William A. 1920-46, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS--Education--Smith College] (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - Nelson, Mrs. Max, National Federation of Settlements 1928-29 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Neurath, Otto 1931-37, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Industrial Relations Institute--Subjects] (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - O 1922-38 (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - Oak, Liston M. 1934-35 (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Obenauer, Marie 1920-25 (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - Odencrantz, Louise 1929 (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - Ogburn, William F., [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--National Research Council] (Box 27)
    - Orgler, Hertha 1934-39 (Box 27, Folder 49)
    - Otlet, Paul, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Industrial Relations Institute--Subjects] (Box 27)
    - P 1905-51 (Box 27, Folder 50)
    - Page, Kirby 1921-22 (Box 27, Folder 51)
    - Park, Marion Edwards, Bryn Mawr College 1934-35 (Box 27, Folder 52)
    - Park, Robert E., [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--National Research Council] (Box 27)
    - Parker, Albert 1929 (Box 27, Folder 53)
    - Paul-Sachs, T. 1933-35 (Box 27, Folder 54)
    - Peabody, J. Paul, Rocky Mountain Fuel Company, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation-- Special Projects--Rocky Mountain Fuel Company] (Box 27)
    - Perkins, Frances 1932-43, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--U.S. Department of Labor] (Box 27, Folder 55)
    - Person, Harlow S., Taylor Society 1921-33, undated (Box 27, Folder 56)
    - Phelps, Roswell F. 1922 (Box 27, Folder 57)
    - Phillips, Fred L., United Rubber Workers Federal Labor Union 1933-46 (Box 27, Folder 58)
    - Pinchot, Governor Gifford and Cornelia 1923-24 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Plowman, E. Grosvenor 1923-29 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Pollak, Frederick 1938-41, undated, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Refugees] (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Post, Louis F. 1926 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Pouch, E. D. 1930 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Price, George W. 1892-99, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Pryll, Dr. Walter 1939-40 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Q 1931-46 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - R 1904-05, 1918-58 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Radin, George 1942-45, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES-Countries--Yugoslavia] (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Rautenstrauch, Walter 1938-48 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Redefer, Frederick L. 1934-41 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Resnick, Louis 1928-35 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Roberts, Dr. Holland D. 1944-55 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Robeson, Paul, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES-Council on African Affairs] (Box 28)
    - Robin, Mrs. Eva 1938-39 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Roche, Josephine 1941-47, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation--Department of Industrial Studies--Special projects--Rocky Mountain Fuel Company] (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Roelofs, Henrietta, Young Women's Christian Association1932-1937 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor 1928-38 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D. 1928-31 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Rosholt, Ruth 1923 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Ross, Howard S. 1933-34 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Ruml, Beardsley 1924 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - S 1921-55 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Sand, Rene, International Conference of Social Work 1927-38 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Schacht, Hjalmar 1930 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Schneeweiss, Gertrude 1920-25 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Schneidermann, Rose, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--National Women's Trade Union League] (Box 28)
    - Scudder, Vida D. 1951, [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--Ruth Leonard, SERIES VII. AUDIO VISUAL MATERIALS-Audio materials-Frances Young] (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Seaver, Edwin, Soviet Russia Today 1935 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Selekman, Ben M., Russell Sage Foundation 1922-34 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Seligman, Edwin R. A. 1925-34 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Shakhnovaskaya, S. V. 1933-35, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES-Countries--U.S.S.R.] (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Shapley, Harlow 1948-55 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Sheffield, A. D.1924-25 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Shotwell, James T. 1930-38 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Simms, Florence, Young Women's Christian Association 1920-30 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Smith, Edwin S. 1920-48 (Box 29, Folder 2-3)
    - Smith, Ethel, Women's Trade Union League 1923-31 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Smith, Hilda W., Bryn Mawr Summer School 1932, 1955-58 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Smith, Mattiecirca 1883-98 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Smith, Richard R. 1939-41 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Smyth, F. Hastings, [see SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS--Related Collections--Society of the Catholic Commonwealth] (Box 29)
    - Somerville, Lucy R. 1923 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Soule, George 1923-39 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Spence, W. J. 1924 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Spofford, William B., Church League for Industrial Democracy 1928-50 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Stewart, Paul 1932 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Stone, N. I. 1928-30 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Strong, Anna Louise 1949-50, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES-Countries--U.S.S.R.] (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Strong, Mabel A. 1928 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Stuart, J. Leighton, Yenching University 1930-46 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Sturgis, J. McC. 1928-38 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Suffern, Arthur E., Federal Council of the Churches of Christ 1927 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Survey Associates, Inc.1918-36, [microfilm from Survey Associates Records, University of Minnesota - see SSC Microfilms] (Box 29)
    - T 1904, 1923-34 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Taylor, Don H. 1930-33 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Taylor, Gladys, Young Women's Christian Association 1935-38 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Taylor, Louise M. S. 1929-35 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Tead, Ordway 1927-34 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Thomas, Albert, International Labor Office 1927-31, undated (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Thomas, M. Carey, Bryn Mawr 1924-25 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Thomas, Norman 1930 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Thompson, Huston 1931-41 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - Thorne, Florence C., American Federation of Labor 1927-34 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Tippy, Worth M., Federal Council of the Churches of Christ 1935-38 (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - Trone, S. A. 1935-43 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - Tugwell, Rexford G. 1932-33 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Tyler, Ruth1938-40 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Upham, Maxine 1944 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - Urwick, L., International Management Institute 1929 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - V 1933-61 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - Van der Goot, A. 1947-50 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - van der Leeuw, C. H. 1929-31, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Industrial Relations Institute--Subjects] (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - van der Leeuw, J. J. 1931 (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - van der Lugt, Maria J. A. 1939-44 (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - van Dyke, Brooke, Smith College, Class of 1905, 1904-1905 (Box 29, Folder 40)
    - van Horn, Olive, Young Women's Christian Association 1920-24, 1948 (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - van Wicklen, Frederick, Jr. 1935-36 (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - Varlez, Louis, International Labor Office 1923-25 (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - Villard, Oswald Garrison 1930-34 (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - Vincent, Merle D., Rocky Mountain Fuel Company 1928-38, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation--Department of Industrial Studies--Special projects--Rocky Mountain Fuel Company] (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - von Haan, Hugo 1929-40 (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - Voysey, Brenda, International Industrial Relations Institute (IRI)-1922-32, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Industrial Relations Institute] (Box 29, Folder 47)
    - W 1891-1950 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Wachtel, Dr. Curt 1938-40, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Waite, Benjamin E. 1937, 1956-57 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Wald, Lillian D. 1922-1928 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Warburg, Paul M. 1929-31, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Weigert, Oscar 1933 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Weiland, Dr. Ruth 1930-46 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Wells, Dorthea, Smith College Class of 1904, 1902-05 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Wells, Marguerite M., National League of Women Voters 1937 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - White, William A. 1936 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Wibaut, F. M., International Industrial Relations Institute (IRI) 1931-35 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Wieck, Edward A. 1934-43, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES--Coal Industry] (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Wilbrandt, Robert 1931-35 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - William, Maurice, Yenching University 1928-32 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Williams, Whiting 1928 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Willits, Joseph H. 1928-40 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Winslow, Emma 1927-28 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Wolf, Robert 1927 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Wood, Margaret Wells, Young Women's Christian Association 1922-24 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Wood, Mildred L., Young Women's Christian Association 1922-29 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Woodcock, Sarah, MvK's childhood teacher 1891-93 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Woodsworth, Hon. S. J. 1924 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Wunderlich, Frieda 1928-31 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Y 1923-39 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Yergen, Max, International Committee of African Affairs 1938-40 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Young, Owen D. 1923-35 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Yule, Herbert, National Research Council 1923-25 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Z 1924-29, 1941 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - zu Schwabedissen, Dr. Meyer, International Industrial Relations Institute 1930-32 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Newspapers
    - General 1911-33 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - The Daily Compass 1950-51, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Sophia Smith Collection 1953-81, undated (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - Unidentified correspondence 1893-1961 (Box 31)
- SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES1906-1961
  - Publications listed by publisher, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 31)
  - Monographs
    - Artificial Flower Makers 1913 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Women in the Bookbinding Trade 1913 (Box 32)
    - Wages in the Millinery Trade, J. B. Lyon Company 1914 (2 copies) (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Working Girls in Evening Schools: A Statistical Study 1914 (Box 32)
    - A Seasonal Industry: A Study of the Millinery Trade in New York 1917 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Employes' Representation in Coal Mines: A Study of the Industrial Representation Plan of the Colorado Fuel and Iron Company 1924 (Box 32)
    - 4 Miners and Management: A Study of the Collective Agreement between the United Mine Workers of America and the Rocky Mountain Fuel Company 1934 (Box 32)
    - Creative America: Its Resources for Social Security 1936 (2 copies) (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Technology and Livelihood, 1944 (2 copies) (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Articles, reprints, and published statements, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation; Oversize Materials]
    - "Working Hours for Factory Women," Charities and the Commons6 Oct. 1906 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - "Child Labor in New York City Tenements," in Charities and the Commons, 18 Jan. 1908 (Box 34)
    - "Some Problems of Method in Investigations of Women's Work," Committee on Women's Work, Russell Sage Foundation, [unpublished]circa 1908 (Box 34)
    - "What Alumnae are Doing: Some Facts and Some Theories About Women's Work," in Smith Alumnae QuarterlyJan. 1911 (Box 34)
    - "Women and Children Who Make Men's Clothes," The Survey1 Apr., 1911 (Box 34)
    - "A Vocation Bureau for Women," [published in a YWCA publication] 12 Mar. 1912 (Box 34)
    - "Working Conditions in New York City Department Stores," The Survey, 15 July 1913 (Box 34)
    - "Facts About Wage-Earners in the United States Census," New York School of PhilanthropyOct. 1915 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - "Positions in Social Work," New York School of PhilanthropyFeb. 1916 (2 copies) (Box 34)
    - "For Women in Industry: The Proposed New Division in the Department of Labor," The Survey23 Dec. 1916 (Box 34)
    - "Storage Bulletin No. 9 on the Employment of Women in the Storage and Warehousing Depots of the United States Army," 24 Nov. 1917 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - "Labor Policies in the War," [unpublished] Jan. 1918 (Box 34)
    - "Woman and Her Place in War Industries," Manufacturers News21 Mar. 1918 (Box 34)
    - "Case Work and Social Reform," The AnnalsMay 1918 (Box 34)
    - "A Census of College Women," Journal of the Association of Collegiate AlumnaeMay 1918 (Box 34)
    - "Women in the Munition Industries," Life and LaborJune 1918 (Box 34)
    - "The Government and the Women in Industry," [written for American Federationist] 1918 (Box 34)
    - "Statement Prepared…for Good Housekeeping Magazine," 23 Dec. 1918 (Box 34)
    - "Federal Policies for Women in Industry," The AnnalsJan. 1919 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - "Standards for the Employment of Women in Industry," U.S. Department of Labor1 Mar. 1919 (Box 34)
    - "Women Workers During Reconstruction," American Labor Legislation ReviewMar. 1919 (Box 34)
    - "New Standards for Negro Women in Industry," Life and LaborJune 1919 (Box 34)
    - "Women In Industry After the War," [written for Vassar Quarterly], Nov. 1919 (Box 34)
    - "What They Think of You," by Helen J. Ferris, based upon MvK's research, Green Book Magazine, Mar. 1921 (Box 34)
    - "Women and Machines," Atlantic MonthlyFeb. 1921 (Box 34)
    - "What are Women in Industry Laws," Union SignalJan. 1922 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - "The Professional Organization of Social Work," The AnnalsMay 1922 (Box 34)
    - "Unemployment Ended?," The SurveyJune 1922 (Box 34)
    - "The Moral Challenge of Industry," Department of Christian Social Service 1922 (Box 34)
    - "Florence Simms," The Woman's Press, Apr. 1923 (Box 34)
    - "Equal Rights: Arguments Pro and Con for A Woman's Equal Rights Constitutional Amendment," Journal of the American Association of University WomenJan. 1924 (Box 34)
    - "Promotion in the Smith Faculty," The Smith Alumnae QuarterlyMay 1924 (Box 34)
    - "The Association's Relation to the Social and Economic Position of Women," Journal of the American Association of University WomenOct. 1924 (Box 34)
    - "Uncle Sam and the Women Care," National League of Women Voterscirca 1924 (Box 34)
    - "Sharing Management With the Workers," The Adult Bible Class Magazine, circa 1924 (Box 34)
    - "Labor and Capital - Partners in Practice," [written for The Survey]8 Jan. 1925 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - "Child Labor In 1925: An Opportunity for Effective Action," The Churchman24 Jan. 1925 (Box 34)
    - "Employes' Representation in Steel and Coal," The New Republic25 Feb. 1925 (Box 34)
    - "Ten Years of the Rockefeller Plan, Compared with Five Years of Employes' Representation at the Dutchess Bleachery" Survey GraphicFeb. 1925 (Box 34)
    - "Equal Rights Cannot Be Won By Constitutional Amendment," American Association of University WomenMar. 1925 (Box 34)
    - "The Participation of Wage-Earners in Management," Safety EngineeringMar. 1925 (Box 34)
    - "Issues in Research Method," Service Bulletin of Personnel Research FederationMay 1925 (Box 34)
    - "Employes' Representation in Steel-How Has It Worked?," [Written for The Blast Furnace and Steel Plant]18 June 1925 (Box 34)
    - "Procedure Followed in Studying the Industrial Representation Plan of the Colorado Fuel ad Iron Company," Journal of Personnel Research, Aug.-Sept. 1925 (Box 34)
    - "Human Relation in Industry: The Church League for Industrial Democracy," 5 Sept. 1925 (Box 34)
    - "New Italian Work in New York at Church of the Holy Communion," The Witness17 Sept. 1925 (Box 34)
    - "The Church and Industrial Life-What Has Been Done Since 1922?," The Witness24 Sept. 1925 (Box 34)
    - "Employes' Representation: an Analysis of the Rockefeller Plan," Homiletic ReviewSept. 1925 (Box 34)
    - "The Task of a Trustee," Smith Alumnae QuarterlyMay 1926 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - "Modern Industry and Society," American FederationistJune 1926 (Box 34)
    - "Justice and the Individual," Workers' EducationAug. 1926 (Box 34)
    - "The Interview as a Method of Research," Taylor SocietyDec. 1926 (Box 34)
    - "Foreword," in "The Forty-Eight-Hour Law, Do Working Women Want It?," The Consumer's League7 Jan. 1927 (Box 34)
    - "Barometers of Unemployment," [written for Springfield Republican]1 Mar. 1927 (Box 34)
    - "Employment Statistics Key to Economic State," Springfield Sunday Union and Republican12 Mar. 1927 (Box 34)